Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well. Today, I'm going to
talk about traveling with kids,
traveling with children. This is
something that is on my mind because I
just recently traveled to Europe, first
to Greece,
and then 2 days in Paris
with my family, my wife, and my two
children. And my kids are very young. My
son is still 4 years old. He's almost 5.
And my daughter is 2 years old. They are
both very young.
And many people
decide not to travel a lot when they
have young children because it can be
complicated.
But I did this trip with my kids. It was
so much fun.
And now,
today, I'm going to talk a little bit
about the differences between traveling
with young children and traveling
without young children. Remember that if
you want my training to help you listen
better and understand native speakers
better, then make sure to sign up for my
membership, and you'll get my
specialized listening training. That
link is down below.
Okay.
Let's talk about traveling with
children. Specifically,
for me, traveling with young children.
Well, the first thing I think of
when I think about traveling with
children
is the flight.
Flying to
the place where you're going.
This can be complicated.
Thankfully,
the planes that we were on
had entertainment.
Meaning, they had screens to watch
things.
When you have this,
it's a very big help because
children can watch movies and TV shows
for hours
uh on the plane using these screens.
That's what my children did. Uh that's
one of the things that they did. So,
this really helped.
But, also, they slept on the plane.
Many times when you travel far with
children,
they get tired and need to sleep.
Sometimes, we need to sleep on the
plane.
Adults, too.
But, my children also fell asleep on the
planes.
That's also
helpful.
That takes time, right? And the food is
also helpful. They serve you food on the
plane, and
that's good for kids, usually. So,
uh flying can be complicated with kids,
but with the entertainment,
sleeping, eating,
it's possible.
It was not very hard for us, thankfully.
So, that's one thing.
How about packing for the vacation?
When you have small children,
you need to pack different things that
you don't normally pack.
You need to pack diapers if you have a
small child or a baby.
We had to bring diapers. We had to bring
a lot of clothes. And
kids often
get messy, meaning they spill food on
their clothes, they have accidents.
So, they need
a lot of clothes.
So, you have to pack differently.
Another thing is transportation
when you are in the country or the city
that you're going to.
With small children,
it can be a little complicated
to take public transportation,
uh especially if the children have to
stand up on the bus or on the train, the
metro.
My kids had to do this, and they
uh almost fell down
on the public transportation,
that can be a little hard. Uh we also
rented a car
in Greece.
This makes it easier for kids because
you can just drive places.
But, you have to rent cars with car
seats for the children, right? Uh so,
you have to pay extra.
Another thing that is uh different when
you're traveling with young children
is that it's more difficult to take
an Uber or other
ride-sharing
um cars like that because they don't
have car seats, usually. So, uh
sometimes
uh they won't take you. But, you can
usually still take a taxi.
Uh
another thing that is different
is uh walking around
when you travel
uh with kids, you can't walk
that far. You can't walk that much
because kids
don't like walking
for very long. They complain.
They don't want to walk a lot. So, you
can't do many, many things walking
around while traveling.
You have limits when you're traveling
with young children.
My kids walked a lot in Greece
and in Paris,
but my daughter
gets tired easily. So, we had to carry
her while we walked. Uh my son walked a
lot, but he also got tired, too. So, we
had to
uh be careful and not do too much with
the kids because
it's very tiring to walk and go up and
down stairs.
In Greece, there are many many stairs to
go up and down. So, that can be hard
with kids. That's a little bit
different.
Also, the things that you decide to do
are
usually different when you travel with
kids because
kids don't want to do the same things
that you want to do.
Kids want to do other things. So,
sometimes you have to do what your kids
want to do so they can have fun. And
then maybe they can do what you want to
do. Right? Uh you have to
think about your kids and what type of
fun activities
they want to do, where they want to go.
That's another thing you need to think
about. And another thing that can be
complicated
when you travel with young children
is when you go to restaurants, Uh
depending on the country and the city.
Uh
in the US,
it's very easy in most places
to go to restaurants with your children.
Uh it's very normal.
However, I know that in some countries,
some places,
it's not very normal to take your young
children uh to a nice restaurant,
for example. So,
it can be a little hard to go to
all the restaurants you want to go to if
you have little kids.
When we were in Europe,
at some restaurants, they didn't have
chairs for children. And many times, my
children were the only children in the
restaurant. So,
it can be a little complicated when you
go to restaurants in other countries
with your children, but this depends on
the country, like I said. Here in the
US,
it's not a big problem. It's very easy
to go to many different restaurants with
your children. They have high chairs,
the chairs for babies, little kids.
It's
very nice. But, in some places, they
don't have this. So,
those were some of the things that are
different when you travel with young
children.
It can be hard, but I think that it's
still a great experience. I had a lot of
fun in Europe with my children.
Specifically, my son really liked it. I
think my daughter did, too. I uh
recommend traveling with children if you
can. It's a great experience, and your
children can remember this when they're
older. It's a great family experience.
So, uh that's something that you can
think about, maybe. I hope you enjoyed
this video. If you want to improve your
listening and start to understand native
speakers better, make sure to sign up
for my training, and I'll help you do
that. The link is down below. Thank you
all for listening, and I'll talk to you
in the next video.